All I've got to do is train Justin AI
now and just have him show up on the
podcast and be like, "Guys, look at this
bug." You know, and then my my hand is
going to glitch out and, you know, it's
going to like go through my face or
something.
Yeah, dude.
>> All right, man. Let's roll. Um, we'll
see if my voice holds up today. Somehow
I got a cold again.
>> Uh, so yeah, I'm going to be like muting
and, you know, hacking up along on the
side. See what I did there? Hacking up
along. Uh, I did not catch that. That's
awesome.
>> I should have given you that. I I did
not even catch it. It's such a common
expression. I never even thought about
having the word hacking in it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um, so yeah, it should be an
interesting episode. But um, let's go
ahead and jump into a couple
announcements. First, first thing was
that we are updating our um, crit
research lab exclusivity agreement. So
for any of you all that have been
submitting awesome research to the crit
research lab, thank you guys so much for
that. Um we are changing our agreement a
little bit to be a little bit more uh
liberal here, a little bit more um in
favor of the researcher. Where
previously we um requested that the
researchers would not take the material
and host it anywhere else, leave it on
this on the research lab website, we are
now um giving the researchers the
ability to host it on their own blog as
well after 30 days is up. So um if that
exclusivity agreement was a um you know
deciding factor for you in not
submitting research to the lab then uh
please go ahead and check out the new
agreement uh as I think this would help
a little bit um and and I for those of
you that aren't familiar with it uh this
is a essentially crowdsourced research
lab that we're doing where we will pay
researchers for their research um and
host it on the lab cover it on the pod
that sort of thing. So, lots of extra
distribution and you also get, you know,
we try to buy them dinner at least, you
know, for for the research that they do.
So, if that interests you, definitely
check it out. Um, lab.ctb.show.
And there's been a lot of good research
on there, hasn't there, man?
>> Yeah, it's insane. And I I think that
Justin might be uh filling his own uh
desires here because like I think that
what has been lacking, well, not
necessarily lacking, but what one thing
you see less of and it's because people
are a little bit insecure of like is
this research worthy? is this postw
worthy or whatever is you encouraging
people to basically post like even just
weird gadgets like hey if you have this
weird functionality in this in like in
the browser or in this other thing like
just go ahead and post it and share it
with us and then it ends up being like a
a core component of a chain later on.
>> Yeah, totally. And and actually I'm I'm
glad you mentioned that, dude, because
right before this episode, you and I
were talking about an exploit um sort of
gadget that I'm going to use in a bug
that I've got right now. And this came
up in the critical thinkers chat. Um
which is just yet another reason you
guys should should subscribe to the
critical thinkers tier because there's
just so much gold that goes into that
chat. Um, but one of the guys in there
dropped that. Um, if let's say you have
like an open redirect uh, and but you
only control the the um, you know, the
the protocol specific portion there.
>> Um, you can do some really interesting
stuff with popping it into uh, what is
u,? Let me pull up the actual thing.
It's x dash or safari-https-x,
isn't it? Or or did I get it mixed
around? Uh I don't know the syntax
exactly, but I'd also use this for a
vulnerability on an engagement a few
months ago and it was awesome. It's
really neat. Um you can use it for AI
vulnerabilities specifically if their
protection um is using sec fetch site.
So
>> yeah, it's uh x-afari-https.
Okay. So what's interesting is that also
ends in https uh which is which is nice
for
>> Yeah, exactly.
>> Yeah. So you can pop it open into a
different browser um which is helpful
for leaking stuff sometimes and also uh
gets you into Safari which may have
different client side restrictions than
you'll see in your um other
environments. Um so that that's a pretty
cool little little trick. That's a
perfect example of something that uh you
know we would love to have microblogged
on the lab website. Uh so if you guys
are interested in checking out the lab,
please do that. Um okay, so we do have a
little bit of news to get into today. Uh
before we get into the episode, I will
like let
the hunters know, you know, one of the
one of the core tenants of CTB is that
every episode we're trying to give S
tier hunters, you know, at least one
little tidbit of knowledge that will
further their um hacking skills. This
episode is actually an AMA
focused on um bugbounty.forum, which is
a new environment that we're trying to
support and help hack, you know, hackers
migrate to uh where we can talk about
all things bug bounty. So, we decided to
do an AMA on it. A lot of the stuff
we're going to be answering today is
pretty basic stuff. There there is some
more nuance stuff in there as well, but
uh I do like to give that little, you
know, uh announcement in the beginning
just in case any of you more advanced
hunters would just like to stick around
for the for the new segment today. Um
that being said, in the new segment, I'm
going to cover a super sick technique
that I think every uh you know, top tier
hunter should know about.
A minute ago, Justin was literally just
staring off into space and I thought he
was thinking about how to uh like I
don't know, get these AMA questions
lined up, right? Or thinking about an
answer to one of the AMA questions. I
was like, Justin, what are you just
thinking about? He's like, I'm thinking
about how awesome this this this writeup
is,
>> dude. It's so good, man. I I love
Crossite Leaks so much. Um so anyway,
there's your there's your announcement
um beforehand uh to let you know. Um,
we're going to jump jump right into this
uh write up. This is cross-sight e or e
tag length leak. Um,
and this is by arc arc. Uh, who I I
believe is actually a Japanese
researcher, which is cool. Um, I see
some of the the Japanese in his uh in
his screenshots here. Uh yeah, I think
that's I want to say that's whole
susheen. It's like unprotected. Uh so I
Yeah, HPS. It's not HPS. Um, but anyway,
I wanted to cover this um this write up
because I think this is a really cool
cross-sight leak and it shows what is
possible with just a little little
modification. Um, and being able to leak
just one extra bite. Um, so let me go
ahead and and jump into this. Uh, this
was a a CTF challenge for uh, Seccon.
Um, and it was authored by Ararkarch.
uh and it takes a bunch of different
primitives here on how to leak the flag
cross origin. So the first thing that's
interesting is the E tag header length
and um one of one of the very uh cool
pieces about uh the E tag is that a lot
of times it's implemented using a hex
string. Okay. So sometimes depending on
the size of the response um I I'll read
this uh here this quote from the um from
the article. It says because the size is
encoded in hex the number of hex digit
changes at boundaries. For example 0x FF
goes to 0x 1000 right which has four
characters rather than three. This means
the ET uh or the E tag length can differ
by one depending on whether the response
size crosses such a boundary. Um so uh
in this specific challenge we control
the response size by abusing curve to
create many notes in the victim session
and this allows us to manipulate the
total response size so that if you if
you create a search hit it it has a you
know it crosses that boundary and makes
the E tag one longer and if you search
you know and have the response uh the
miss response then it will be uh a
shorter length in the E tag header
Um, and uh, that is just freaking sick,
man. Um, and and the way that this works
is when you when you send a search, the
the site will return the E tag header,
right?
>> And then when you send that same um
search again, that that um value that's
in the E tag header will then be placed
into the um, if none match header right
here. Right. So, so the value from that
original uh E tag response header which
contains you know that that bite that
could be one longer or one not longer
gets put into the request right and then
what what they use here is they use um
the 431 status code error which is a
part of Node.js JS, right? Which says
that I know, dude. Isn't this crazy?
This is so sick.
>> This is absurd,
>> right? So, if you if you nudge your
request right up to this um 16 kilobyte
limit on the size of headers, which
includes the the request um uh like
query, so you can pad a bunch in the in
the like an X query parameter or
whatever. then that the the differential
between that one bite that gets put in
the E tag header will result in a 431
which would indicate a a hit versus uh
you know a 200 which would indicate a
miss right and and this is you know uh a
a browser functionality here that uh you
know obviously the server is returning
the 431 but the browser functionality
that we use to determine the difference
is uh whether or not that that 431 is
actually placed into the browser history
or not because the history API right has
this function called should replace
current entry and where it it decides
between pushing into the history versus
replacing the current entry and if it is
a a 431
um then that's going to be
you know replaced versus if it's an
actual navigation a 200 right then it
will uh be added to the history Right?
So if your if your history length is one
shorter, even cross origin, you can tell
whether it was a 431 or a 200, right?
Which allows you to get a yes no answer
on whether a search hit or didn't hit.
And then using that, you can binary
search and brute force all the
characters of the flag cross origin with
a cross-sight leak.
>> That is ridiculous. Did anyone solve
that?
>> How sick is that?
>> Did it Did it say it was solved one
time?
>> Let me see. Hold on. Let's see the top.
difficulty one of 5,000
>> one solve
crazy dude um I just I just love that
this uses just a one bite difference in
the length of a header right
>> to leak an entire flag
>> to leak the flag
frick dude I I love it so um anyway I
hope that explanation made sense um I'll
go ahead try to summarize it here at the
end. Um the the E tag header which is
returned from the server will be one
bite longer in some specific scenarios,
right? Um and that value will be
reflected into your request the next
time you try to hit that endpoint,
right? To see if there's a cache caching
compatibility here, right? Using that
reflected value into the header, right?
You can determine uh you know yes or no
whether that extra bite was added. uh by
you know
cushioning right up to that uh 16
kilobyte limit that gives you a 431.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. And if the 431 is returned, then
that entry will replace the current
entry in um in the history API versus
adding to the history API, which then
once you navigate back to an origin you
control, you can check the length of the
history and determine whether or not it
was a 431 or not, which gives you a yes
or no on whether
>> I didn't I didn't response
>> I didn't realize the history.length
thing was required, too. Yeah, that's a
really nice that's a really nice cross-
sight leak primitive. Um I've seen that
used quite a bit. Um so yeah, I guess
just kind of taking this to a higher
level, dude, like paying attention to
these really small details like that,
>> you know, uh like just a one bite
difference in the encoding of of the of
the hex can result in some of these uh
cross- sight leaks, which is astounding
in my opinion.
>> Absolutely astounding. Yeah, this is I
don't know like the orange side of front
end.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Seriously, these CTF guys
are insane, man. Really?
>> Yeah.
>> All right. What you got in the news?
>> Um something small and and neat. Uh it's
called Claudis. Um or maybe it's called
Claude.
>> I'm trying to find the notes. Yeah.
Claudebot.
>> Claudebot. Claude.
>> Yeah, it's it's kind of confusing. I
we'll put it in the show notes, but
there's basically like a guy on X was
saying, "Hey, I saw that this other guy
named Stipe was building Claudius.ai and
that's CL L A W D I S.AI and I was
intrigued. So, I just told Claude Code
to stand up Claudis for me and I call it
CLA crawad
>> and it did and it did it all for
itself." And it's basically just like
using Claude code, like using like um an
agent but from WhatsApp. And so it feels
much more natural, like you're like
messaging your friend or something like
that. But then he wanted to send an
audio message. So he was like literally
in the car or something like waiting for
his wife to go get groceries. And so he
sent a WhatsApp audio message and was
like, "Hey, you know, figured this out,
you know, and so it basically installed
Whisper CPP via and like then use that
to listen to his audio message to then
start doing that." But anyways, I just
think that the being able to control
your AI agents from WhatsApp seems
really cool, especially if it's um and
like you know, people have built that
before, but it's not been like cloud
code under the hood. And I think cloud
code under the hood is really where
there's a lot of power. And I've been
using cloud code from a VPS where it can
basically play DevOps engineer for me to
like, you know, reconfigure things or
stand up PC's or whatever.
>> And so when I want to mess with it, I
always have to like open term and like
type really small in a terminal on my
phone. that just sounds really
miserable. Whereas if I could just send
an audio message and be like, "Hey, like
let's try a new design on this website,
you know, that I'm pinging or playing
with for just my family or whatever. Um,
in an audio message on like WhatsApp
that feels like it would be much more
fun and clean and good." And so um I
thought that was really cool. You guys
can check out um that at just claw claw
wis.ai.
>> Nice. Yeah, I I think that's I think
that's nice to have, you know,
especially on your PC server, you know,
adding something to your PC or something
like that. Um,
making it a little bit more convenient
with text messages or or, you know,
WhatsApp or whatever. Also pretty
smooth. I like it.
>> Yeah. And I've been doing um hopefully
that this is not leaking anything. I've
been doing um more hacking of those sort
of things. Actually, I think I did tell
you that basically Gro Gro and Tesla is
adding more features and so being able
to just via voice test little payloads
and stuff feels like feels like the
future. You know, it's like I'm doing
prompt injection hacking in my car while
I'm driving and similar things for like
Google's adding more and more like AI
like Gemini to Google Maps and
directions and stuff. And so I think
that um there's some there's some really
neat room for attacks there that people
should try. So
>> totally totally Yeah, I think that I
think also I've said in the past I'm
using Gemini CLI more
I think it's got to be Claude Code, man.
I think a lot of people are saying
Claude Code is like really really doing
wonderful stuff for them. And I have
been running into some issues lately
with Gemini. So, I think even though I
kind of I kind of believe that Gemini
will eventually win the whole like AI
thing, you know, or be the leader, um I
think for the time being, I got to hop
on the the Cloud Code train. So
>> yeah, when there's no spin up or when
there's no like spin up um friction and
you just start start using it, it's like
why not just try out the best one and
then if you want to switch back to
Gemini CLI in a month, it's like it will
take you an extra 10 minutes to copy and
paste over a prompt or something, right?
So
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yeah. I feel like the
switching cost is not very high.
>> Yeah.
>> Um all right, man. Actually, I'm going
to cut this next um news item so we can
just jump right into the episode because
that cross- sight e tag leak thing was
like was nuts. So, let's jump right into
it. Um, so like I said before,
bugbounty.forum, awesome place. You guys
should check it out. We we really would
like to support that environment. Um,
and
>> let me tell people just really quickly
what it is. So, basically, it's an
anonymous forum for bug bounty hunters
where there's not like it's it's almost
like stateless in a way. You basically
get given a UU ID number and you just
use that to log in. You don't have to
like even store credentials or anything
like that. And you can't even really
edit your profile at the moment. But one
thing that's really neat is you can
upload anonymously your bug bounty
earnings. So you and you know that's
also optional. You don't have to do it.
But if you do do that, then you know
it's kind of um proof of like validation
that you know what you're talking about.
You know if you found a significant
number of vulnerabilities or what have
you. And so that's pretty that's pretty
neat. Um I think that's makes it kind of
like fun and exciting and you like kind
of like know who to listen to. Obviously
bug bounty earnings are everything. We
know plenty of people who have made
plenty of money from Bugab Bounty that
maybe aren't the the wisest or the, you
know, the people you want to necessarily
listen to, but at the very least, it's
like a really like, hey, this person at
least knows what they're talking about
when it comes to like technical skill
or, you know, this person is is worth
listening to because they've at least
dabbled enough and they've submitted
enough bugs to have a good experience
with plenty of programs or what have
you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I I think that's I think
that's a a good representation of the
situation. you know, I I I think at the
end of the day, we're in a PC or GTFO
industry and the the proof is that you
have earnings, you know,
>> so um
>> and it's like it's like Reddit, I guess,
is one other thing. It basically you
upvote and downvote comments and post
and um so it seems like a nice place and
a cool place to like start discussing
things from a bug binding perspective.
And there's been a lot of people that
have migrated over there. So
>> yeah. Yeah. And I think POME is putting
a lot of work into it um and shipping
new features quickly and it works well
on mobile which is nice. So uh yeah cool
cool place and we're going to do an AMA
from there. Um so we selected a bunch of
different questions. Now um when we
posted the uh the AMA uh people got
really wordy with their uh questions uh
which was not expected but as you can
see a lot of these questions are like
super long. So, we took a couple of them
and and or we took all of them and fed
them into AI and kind of extracted the
core question behind um a lot of them,
but we'll try to also jump back over and
um address the actual questions directly
um as we can. So, I guess how we'll do
that um Joseph is if one person is, you
know, answering it, we can kind of go
back and make sure with the original
question uh whether we're catching the
the nature of it. Does that sound good?
>> Okay. Yeah, sounds good.
>> Okay, awesome. So, the first one that
came up was, "Will bug hunting become
obsolete due to AI agents in the next
five or 10 years by Granite Glitcher."
Uh, I'm going let you take that one,
dude.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think that the concern
here, you know, the person later on in
their question, Granite Glitcher says,
you know, if we're being honest, in
their opinion, it's not a good idea for
newbies to get into this industry.
Howard Jr. is supposed to stand a
chance, you know, etc., etc. I yeah I
don't think that bug bounty is going to
be gone in 5 to 10 years like not even
close but I do think that it is going to
be more competitive. So if you're going
to get into it I think you need to make
sure that you are kind of supercharged
right and I think that's going to be
true across a lot of industries. AI
lowers the barrier to entry to get into
into new fields like or just into fields
in general. And then it also lowers the
barrier to entry of like going from hey
I know a little bit to I can do cool
stuff right like if you just know a
little bit now you can like work with
cloud code or whatever to build a cool
tool or a cool thing and you can also
because of the internet get really quick
feedback on like how it's going. So, I
would say, you know, should beginners
get into bug bounty, yeah, I I still
think bug bounty is like the like an
overlap of you're going to build real
skills that are valuable to huge
corporations. You are going to um build
your resume as well. You know, sometimes
you can have skills, but it won't
necessarily translate to a resume. Bug
bounty findings do like kind of directly
translate to resumes even if all you did
was go do all of labs, right? like being
able to say you've done those like
actual real validation of like real
training that you've done. Um you you
obviously have the potential for money
and then it's in an industry where like
if you are able to kind of succeed it's
freaking fun. Like you get to go on like
cool trips and stuff, live hacking
events.
>> Um and the flexibility like there's no
sales, there's no like meeting of you
know a lot of people I think don't love
sales or they don't love you know face
to face interactions with customers or
whatever. So if you're like that type of
person and you really want that flex and
free ability then or freedom and
flexibility, then it also has that. So I
would say go into it, but go into it
knowing like, hey, I'm probably going to
want to use AI to supercharge myself.
I'm going to want to build my own tools.
I'm going to want to eventually maybe
transition to some like hardware hacking
because I think that'll be more
defensible long term as well.
>> Yeah, I agree. I agree with that and I
think you answered the core of the
question. I will I will add I think AI
is just another layer of automation on
top of it. ensure it it targets a little
bit more manualesque hunting um more
than other you know automation
breakthroughs that we've had in the past
like cloud and and you know kubernetes
and stuff like that um but at the end of
the day it's still a it's just like
another hacker that has their own set of
eyes right and it's going to miss stuff
um and sure they can throw it at it a
thousand times right um and maybe the
compute will get such that they can do
that and you know really tweak the
temperature and stuff like that but um I
think it's just going to be another
hacker you know and there are so many
hackers looking at the same scope we
find crit after crit after crit on after
live hacking event you know and uh and
so I I really do think that it is uh bug
bounty industry is going to be just fine
especially with all the crappy code
written by AI to help balance out the
the table you know
>> yeah the number of people who are
developing apps these days is like way
higher so like you said there's also
going to be way more opportunities for
vulnerabilities. And I would just and I
would just say this, like
>> if bug bounty goes away, almost every
industry is going away. And at that
point, you know, like we're just in like
a different situation as a society,
right? It's like we need to solve this
with UBI or whatever, you know, or maybe
we'll be flourishing or maybe it will be
some huge great depression, but it's not
going to uniquely negatively impact Bug
Bounty. It's going to impact a lot more
if if and when that does ever happen.
But I think it'll be slow and gradual,
and I think that it'll be fine. So
>> yeah, I agree, man. Um, let's move on to
some of these questions by Furious
Beacon. Uh, which ones you think is best
to start
>> here? Let me ask you, I think, um, it's
a good question. What are ways to get
invited to a live hacking event if
you're not a top tier hacker, Justin?
>> Um,
well, the live hacking events are kind
of for the top tier hackers. Uh, there
there are some like I don't know how
Hacker One selects these, but I have
seen like some mentees that get to come
to the live hacking events. I think
they're normally like local hackers. Um
I guess the the short answer to this
would be specialize in one program that
that has live hacking events. You know,
scour
>> and that was a lighter question like
what companies run live events so we can
tell them kind of
>> Yeah.
>> which types of companies. It's usually
>> that as a exercise to the listener
because sometimes they don't want us to
talk about them, you know.
>> No, no, no. I was going to talk about it
as a category. It's basically large
companies that are able to afford live
hacking events. Yeah.
>> Like, you know, you're going to be
looking at more at like within the f
within the Fortune 20, let's say,
>> there's going to be, you know, five or
10 companies there that are running live
hacking events. Um, and so I think, you
know, targeting these like larger
companies that can afford to buy live
events and getting in their good grace
is a great way to get invites.
>> I agree. Yeah, I I think that's pretty
much the only way. If you're not like a
generally top tier hacker, the the best
way is going to be to specialize in one
program and get invited as a specialist.
>> I I do think you can um and please don't
blow people up, but if you're adding
value to their life, that's different. I
would say I think another good way is to
become good friends with somebody who
gets invited a lot and and and you know,
ask for a plus one.
>> And and the best way to do that is to
send them high quality leads, high
signal leads. don't message them and say
hey or say hi or say whatever. But if
you have like a lead that you you know
think could be either escalated from
like a medium to a crit or whatever or
you have a you know a higher crit that's
like almost a bug that but that you
can't get past like a specific thing or
whatever. If you send that to bug
hunters that you know are going to live
events and you develop a relationship
with them where you guys are collabing
on the regular then when they're invited
they would probably be open to giving
you a plus one. And I have heard of lots
of hackers including me and um including
Douglas um including others who
basically were a plus one at an event.
They did well and then they got more
invites. So that's probably another
path.
>> I was a plus one of a plus one.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Totally man. I agree. And
and I will to echo what you said like
giving you know like coming to a more
experienced hacker with an actual bug is
like you know the best way for us to
know that you're not playing around you
know because we get so many DMs like hey
is this vulnerable is this like you know
HTML injection vulnerable or whatever
and I'm like dude come on but if you're
like hey here's this uh you know XSS
with CSP bypass I'm you know like I need
this one little thing to make it you
know, any idea how to do this? Then I'm
going to be a lot more likely to like,
okay, yeah, this guy kind of knows what
he's talking about, you know?
>> Um,
>> yeah. Or another thing is actually kind
of saying, hey, I just found this new
host which seems really vulnerable. Do
you want to like look at it with me? Do
you want to collab and hack on it with
me or something like that? Like that's
another interesting way to do
>> that sounds like a one that would get
you. That wouldn't really quite as much.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yeah. I don't think so. I like Oh, I
clicked on the wrong thing here.
>> A new domain on one of your anchor
programs that you hadn't seen before.
because I I just mostly hack the main
apps, dude. Like I I really really don't
go after a lot of hosts unless I've got
a reason, you know, like if I'm looking
to get if I've got a bug, let's say this
is one scenario. If I've got a bug and
I'm looking to circumvent a W or
something,
>> then I'll uh you know, I'll be able to
do that, right? And I'll I'll go find
the host and and that sort of thing. I
very rarely am I like scanning these
extra domains. It's just not what I It's
just not what I found the most signal
from, you know, in my opinion.
>> Yeah, fair enough.
>> Um, okay. Let's see. Next one.
>> Ask You could ask me number seven if you
want.
>> Uh, okay. Is it Let me ask you this.
>> Is it better to do Bug Bounty full-time
or treat it like a nineto-ive job with
fixed hours?
>> Yeah, I would say as a as a father or as
a person with like other obligations
like maybe you're taking care of your
parents or maybe you do have a full-time
job,
>> I I definitely think time boxing it is
the way to go. um from a lifestyle
design perspective, but that's not going
to get you the types of results if
you're trying to level up. So, when I
was, you know, getting into Bug Bounty,
it felt like it was all I thought about.
It was all I worked on. It was like in
the evenings. It was all I did. It was
like I was falling asleep at my
computer, literally. Like, I was laying
in bed with my laptop on my thing and I
would wake up with it in my lap because,
you know, it required that kind of
passion to get into um for success. But,
you know, now because I'm a full-time
hunter, I do time box it to, you know,
basically 8 to 5 or 8 to 4:30. Um, and
that works for me.
>> And we do we do that pretty
aggressively, I think.
>> Yeah.
>> And and and I think that, you know, I
guess it remains to be seen for you, but
for me, I think that is one of the
things that's contributed to the
longevity of my full-time bug bounty
hunting career is is that you do have,
you know, healthy boundaries and stuff
like that.
>> So, yeah. I mean, I think this is
traditional advice you see on like
hustle Twitter, but you know, in the
beginning, you need to put in some
freaking hours and you need to get good
at something and you need to hustle
>> and then as you get good at something,
>> the way that you stay in the game is you
adopt something that gives you
longevity. And and I I'll actually even
call out I'll call out a couple hunters
that that uh that I know. Like Fron is
one of the guys that that always really
amazes me with this. like, you know, he
goes so hard. He goes so hard on
hunting.
>> But even now, like I see him put up
boundaries with his hunting. You know,
even as one of the one of the the more
like just go ham until you die, you
know, hunters that I've ever met. You
know, he he does have to put up
boundaries with his hunting to make sure
that he, you know, has longevity. Um, so
I think it's a non-negotiable for for
for full-time hunters to to have some
sort of like I guess structure to it.
>> Um,
>> yeah. And and I'll add one more thing at
the end here, which is that that really
golden nugget from the Fron episode uh
that we did a while back, which was
that, you know, he says close the laptop
right when you're about to find find
something. And I'm like, dude, what is
wrong with you, man? Like that is
hecked. But often times I do I do find
myself doing that nowadays where I'm
like, "Okay, wow. I just found like this
sick little like sub app on a website
that's got a bunch of extra routes and
I'm like really excited to hit it and
I'm like, you know what? I'm gonna do
that tomorrow, you know, and I'm just
like clawing at my desk to get back to
it the next day, you know?"
>> Yeah, I think that's really smart. I
don't know if I have the I don't know if
I have the self-control to do it,
though.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it does take some for sure.
But I I think you've done a good job of
that this year. Um in your in your first
year of of full-time bug bounty.
>> I appreciate it. I I I was surprised you
highlighted this question. So I want to
ask you this one.
>> It says, "What's better, 10 bugs at five
grand or one bug at five grand?"
>> Yeah. I mean,
>> sorry. 10 10 bugs at five grand total.
Should clarify that. Yes.
>> Or finding one bug at five grand.
>> Yeah. Uh yeah. I I wanted to actually
kind of debate this with you a little
bit and see what what you think. I mean,
yeah, obviously I personally think the
one bug at five grand
>> is better, right? Like I just because
one report, you know,
>> obviously it's a more impactful bug,
that sort of thing. But also like
there's a momentum aspect, you know,
like would I rather find 10 bugs and get
five five grand out of it,
>> you know, especially as a beginner that
might feel really good.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, and it might suggest it might
give you more intel
>> on what this program is vulnerable to.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Right. Like, okay, I've got
10 bugs. I've got a pretty good profile
of like, okay, this program's vulnerable
to this, to this, to this, to this, to
this. Right.
>> Yeah. I mean, I think personally, if you
just think about it from like a
business, you like we we it's funny, we
used this word off air earlier, but it
it definitely derisks you to find more
bugs at a lower value.
>> Um, you have a smoother income earning
curve. Um, but there's no doubt that
there's more prestige and skill required
to find critical bugs. And there's no
doubt that companies care more about
those rit large in regards to invites,
in regards to respect that you have from
them, in regards to like kudos and
thanks and all those things. So, you
know, I think if you had to answer that
question and you knew you were going to
get both, you would do one bug at 5K.
But the thing is most people don't know
they're going to necessarily do that.
I'm a big fan of, you know, report all
the bugs unless they're unless it's a
$100 bug or, you know, an open redirect
or something. I think I'm a big fan of
people, you know, submitting all the
bugs.
>> Yeah. Yeah, I agree with that. Overall,
I think so. I I think the answer to
this, I mean, at first glance, you would
look at this and be like, obviously the
one bug at 5K, but I actually think it
really depends. It depends on where
you're at in your bug bounty journey. It
depends on your relationship with this
target, right? Like if this if this is a
live hacking event target per se or for
example, I I might take the the 10 10 at
five at 5K total because it gives me a
better profile of what this company's
vulnerable to and I'm going to be like
going ham on this company, you know, for
for the next like you know two weeks.
>> Yeah. And it is hard to say what's more
valuable in the minds of the people
because like um this is just like me
talking about my heristics a little bit.
My heristics say that at hacker one live
hacking events volume matters and at
Google AI life hacking events
criticality matters when it comes to
getting MVH let's say.
>> Yeah.
>> Um like the last the last you know
couple Google events like or like like
three out of four of them the MVH is the
person who found the most critical bug
whereas it seems like a lot of times MVH
at Google or at like at um Hacker One
events are often people who got the most
bugs. Yeah, it it is interesting though
because at these Google live hacking
events, you'll often see like only one
or two mega crits. Yep. you know, like
like oh [__] crits, you know, whereas I
feel like at a lot of hacker one life
hacking events, like regardless of the
target,
>> there's a couple
>> you're you're seeing like like, you
know, most everybody's got one, you
know, most everybody of the top
performers has like one oh [__] you
know, oh [__] crit, you know, like
>> um
>> it's funny in my head. I think when
people always act like Google is like
super hardened, I'm always like, yeah, I
agree with you, but yeah, there's bugs
to be found there. But when you say
something like that, it's like maybe
maybe Justin is right. Maybe these
people are right that Google's pretty
hardened.
>> Yeah, I I think it's hardened. I think
it's hardened in a different way,
though. I think I think they use a lot
of measures that that
like prevent the mega crits, right?
>> And and uh and but I do think there's
still a decent amount of like mediums
and and stuff like mediums and highs to
be found. So
>> yeah. Um okay, let's jump back to this
one.
Um, I'm gonna answer this one. What is
the background behind starting CTBB and
how profitable has it been and what is
the long-term plan?
>> Interesting, man. Interesting.
>> Yeah, I'm surprised you highlighted that
one.
>> Yeah. So, the background be a little
vulnerable here.
>> Yeah. The background behind starting CTB
was Joel and I um who was my original
co-host, we loved the conversations we
were having at live hacking events with
other top tier hunters and we wanted
that all the time. And so we wanted to
build a podcast where you can tune in
every week and hear top top tier hunters
um talk about their day-to-day existence
and the things they're passionate about
in technology and and the bugs that they
find and and share some of that like
hype energy. Um so that's that's the
concept. The north star of critical
thinking is to bring and that's why I
added that you know pre-announcement at
the beginning of this episode is to
bring top tier hackers one like
actionable takeaway that affects their
methodology positively per per episode
at least at least. Um and we're going to
continue to try to do that. Um, as far
as how profitable it has been, I'm not
going to give you an exact number, but
it was around seven or eight% of my
income uh for 2025. Um, and this is the
first year,
no, I guess it was a little bit
profitable last year. Um, this is the
first year that it has been like, you
know, move the needle at all profitable.
>> Yeah. Um, and then what is your
long-term plan? Um, yeah, it's an
interesting question. Uh, I think I I
really love CTB. One of the things that
is interesting for me is that um it does
take away the 100% freedom that you have
as being a full-time hunter, right? Like
I've still got to ship a piece of
content every single week to you guys,
you know? And uh that is that is a
burden. I'm not going to lie. Uh it
really is. and and I want it to be high
quality and I want it to be, you know,
to move the needle for top tier hunters.
So, um, as far as my long-term plan, I
think that's still up in the air. For
the time being, I'm I'm definitely going
to keep doing the podcast. We're
bringing on other top tier hunters like
Reszo and Gret um to co-host. Um, I
think as long as I am actively involved
in the in the bug bounty world, I would
like to be doing the podcast as well.
Um, we'll see. One of the things we have
talked about is like adjusting the
frequency or adjusting like um the you
know how often I particularly appear on
the episodes. Um but for the time being
we're locked and loaded for the long
term. We're ready to roll and we're
going to keep adding value to the to the
hackers every week.
>> Maybe AI will come to all our jobs and
then we don't have to do it anymore, you
know.
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, you know, I just all
I've got to do is train Justin AI now
and just have him show up on the podcast
and be like, "Guys, look at this bug."
You know, and then my my hand is gonna
glitch out and, you know, it's gonna
like go through my face or something,
you know. Um,
>> we need somebody in the community to
make an AI fully AI generated episode
just for the laws.
>> Dude, don't put it into Notebook LLM,
man. That thing's going to be like, you
know, it's going to be bad.
>> That's funny.
>> All right. Do you want to jump down to
learning and getting started?
Yeah. Okay. Um, this is interesting. I
would like to ask you this one. Is it
worth finding a mentor if you've only
earned 3.3K USD and don't have any [__]
>> So, I mean, the mentor I I have always
disliked the term mentor. I think you
actually like it more than I do. You've
had lots of mentees and a lot of people
kind of view you as their mentor. Um,
I've always just felt like just be my
friend. Like, let's just let's just
collab and be my friend. I like I think
that like um you know I hate being under
authority and I don't love uh feeling
like less than or more than anyone. And
so you know for me it's like hey let's
just be friends and let's just like talk
about this lead you have or talk about
these bugs you have. Um and you know I'm
not always available so message other
people with the same stuff and that's
totally fine. That's what I did
basically. I never had like a formal
mentor or anything but I definitely
reached out to lots of friends in the
industry and made friends you know to
kind of fill that gap for me. I will say
if you've found $3,000 in bugs, like
great job. There are so many people out
there who have not gotten started or
have never made any money from Bug
Bounty. Um, I would say look at what
worked for you. Like go back and look at
how, you know, how did you find those
bugs? What company was it on? What types
of bugs are you looking for? You know,
how you know, do you have a ton of other
dupes because you're doing something
different that doesn't work? And then
you should focus on what does work. Um,
in general, I think that that's kind of
where my mind goes.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I I think just addressing
the point about like feeling above or or
below someone. I think that's an
interesting point that's not as
compatible with like hacker culture than
uh you know as a lot of things. I would
say I do like that position because it
does allow me to just like give you a
little bit of tough love
>> and and really that that is what I do
with a lot of my mentees. I say like
look
>> here's the deal man. My job, you know,
as your mentor is to tell you how to win
at this, okay? And what you need to do
is this. And you're not doing that.
>> So, you need to do it or you need to,
you know, get real with yourself that
you're not willing to do it, you know?
>> Yeah. And whereas if someone hasn't
asked to be your mentee or if that
relationship's not established, you
wouldn't say that to some like random
friend probably,
>> right? You know, like I mean, I don't
know. Maybe I would, you know, I
>> You're a unique breed. I think I think
you're right though that most people
probably if they want that kind of tough
love and like really great advice, maybe
they do need somebody who's in more of
like a mentor role.
>> Yeah, that does get me in hot water with
some of my friends sometimes is there
are just people out there that are just
not as you know ambitious or you know or
and and I try to tell them like hey you
know the reason that you're not in a
better spot and the reason you're
frustrated is you're not doing XYZ
>> you know and then they are they don't
want to hear that.
um which is their right, you know, and
maybe I I I shouldn't do that without
asking. That's what my wife has told me.
But also, you know, I've seen that
produce really good fruit in people's
lives. Um
>> yeah,
>> so I guess my yes or no on this is is it
worth finding a mentor? Um
you know, a lot a lot of the time what I
say about mentoring and bug bounty is
that it can be a double-edged sword.
like you really need to learn how to
learn on your own
>> to be a bug bounty hunter more than
almost anything else. You know, almost
any other industry you can get a mentor
and that will guide you, you know, that
will help you and accelerate you
>> in bug bounty it can really be a bad
thing too um and and and make you not,
you know, excel as fast as you would if
you just learned how to learn on your
own. So, um I think it's a personal
choice. Um, if you already have found
some success by yourself, I don't know
that I would call 3.3K since mid 2023
a decent amount of success. Um, but
yeah, I mean, clearly you you you know,
found at least one or two bugs.
>> I didn't I didn't realize it was over
three years. Yeah, I'm just looking at
the uh rewarded questions.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Um, you may want to you may
want to look at what you did right in
those reports and try to reproduce that.
Um,
and if you have somebody, you know,
who's willing to mentor you, then maybe
great, but I would say probably not.
>> Yeah. And I do think, you know, I'm we
obviously use AI as a buzz word a lot. I
do especially, but I do think that these
new top models really do make great
mentors. like if like I mean at least
they fill them into a role of like hey
um I'm looking at this I don't know what
to try next right or I'm looking at this
I'm curious if it's vulnerable I'm
looking at this and I'm curious if it
like matches the RFC I'm looking at this
and like I just I just need your help to
like figure out like breakthrough like
give me some ideas for like ways to
bypass this regular expression you know
I think that like we now have like an
unlimited brainstorming partner through
Chad GBT or Claude or whatever so
>> that's a really good point I really like
that. Um, yeah, thanks for that
question, Solid Samurai. Best of luck on
your journey. Um, what you got next?
>> Um, I really I really like this. How do
you conquer a class? For some reason, it
evoked like the class of um in like
video games, like how how did you
conquer this skill? How did you map this
skill tree perfectly? Like as like
Justin did with client side hacking. Um,
and so I think that's a good question.
Yeah. How how do you think that you
conquer like a specific niche or you
know category of vulnerabilities?
>> Okay, so that's the question here by Zen
Apparition. Now my question is long and
about how to conquer a class. Um here's
what he's been going through and doing.
Um yeah, I mean I'm I'm looking at this
and it looks pretty good. Yeah, if
you're if you're the type of person
who's going to type out this long of a
question and the list of your um
strategy, you're probably already on the
right path.
>> Yeah. And and it's it's hitting a lot of
the right areas. So, I I'll read a
little bit out loud for the audio
listeners. He's saying, "Here's what I
did so far. created a personal dashboard
to get you know grasp with HTML CSSJS
started learning about dynamic analysis
learning client side issues CSPT um XSS
iframes sync sources you know all those
sort of thing getting a good grasp by
portfol
pick a program fail miserably
um you know nothing like what I learned
hardly able to make any other sense of
anything and then repeat it right and
I'm like yeah that that that makes sense
you know, you got to do the repeated
part.
>> I do think this person might be somebody
who's falling into overarning. Those
first four those first four points feel
more like overarning. Like I think that
the they need to just stick with the
fail miserably. Just keep failing
miserably as many hours as you can for
the next month and you'll probably stop
failing miserably and you'll probably
start finding stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think that's definitely a
possibility. Um, it's hard to know where
to draw the line for these people, you
know, and say like, "Hey, you're
overarning or you're not overarning."
But really, I would really leverage on
the side of like, "Let me try to figure
this website out that's right in front
of me, you know, that's an actual
target."
>> Yeah.
>> Right. Um,
>> and it does I feel like you do have to
thread the needle with like
>> uh harden programs.
>> Like maybe it makes sense to try to go
with like lower paying programs for this
for a person who's trying to um build up
their front-end skills like that. Yeah,
I I I think this is I I think a good
summary of that, which is like you need
to learn on the target that you're
hacking on, right? So like if you if
you're looking at a target in front of
you and you don't understand something
or you feel like there could be the
potential for a vulnerability, you can
go learn about that vulnerability to
supplement your attack of this specific
target,
>> right? But it's got to be goal oriented
for this specific target, right? So
that's where you kind of mix the actual
hacking and the learning together,
right? Does that make sense?
>> Yep, it does.
>> Yeah, I like that question. Um, thank
you, Zen Apparition. Um, okay. Um, this
one's from Lunar Oracle.
>> It feels It feels a little funny reading
the anonymize names.
>> Yeah. Yeah, it is. You've covered a lot
of different angles on the episodes.
Some feel like real gold mines while
others less so. Do you actually use all
of these angles in your own workflows?
It seems exhausting to apply all of
them.
>> That's a great question. Yeah, I would
say for me personally, definitely not.
you know, I mean, it feels almost
impossible. Um, I do think though,
um, having the tools in the tool set
that, you know, to recall, um, is
something that Justin has mentioned
before. It's like you don't need to
necessarily be an expert in it, but when
you see the thing, it should trigger
your mind to be like, "Oh, I need to go
look up that thing." Whether that be a
cheat sheet, whether that be that video
that you need to go rewatch that segment
of, whether you just remember that it
was Fron Rosen that did it and you need
to DM him, right? Like I think um those
little associations in your mind with
different parts of an app or different
types of vulnerabilities or different
headers or or gadgets like just um
knowing enough and remembering enough
from the episodes to be able to go
reference them is like a huge part of
the value.
>> Yeah, totally agree there. I certainly
don't implement everything we've talked
about on the podcast. Um, I think with
AI stuff I will a little bit more now,
you know, where I can just say to shift,
you know, hey, try this, this, this,
this, this, this, this, right? Um, and I
don't have to manually go do it. Um,
yeah, but it's in there, you know, it's
in my it's in my brain, you know, and
and uh uh just like you said, you know,
being able to go grab that piece of
information when you need it, I think is
really helpful for a more advanced, you
know, hacker. So, yeah,
>> I do think there are some people though,
um, for whom, and for me, especially
when I first got started, that following
methodology really did help.
>> Yeah.
>> Like it was just like, what do I do
next? Oh, just check the step. Just
check check the flow diagram, you know,
or check check the steps. It's like, oh,
what do I do next? Okay. Yeah, what do I
do next? Okay. And then it's like now I
have these interesting endpoints. What
do I do on them? Okay. Well, I check all
of them and every parameter for IDOR and
then I check all of them and every
parameter for XSS. You know, it's like
it doesn't really make sense. Like I'm
checking an API response that's that's
application JSON for XSS and it and it
would never fire. But it's like it's
giving me something to do, right? And
maybe if it and maybe if I maybe if I
did get a payload in, I would be like,
"Oh, why isn't this working?" And then I
would learn that it's not going to fire
because it's coming back as application
JSON, right? And so I I do think
sometimes when you're beginning, um,
methodologies can actually be helpful.
So, I mean, if you wanted to go through
the episodes and come up with a
methodology, especially if it was
through all the episodes or use AI to do
that, I think it'd be really cool if a
listener created like a CTB methodology
based on really cool techniques that
have been mentioned by our community and
on the episodes. But yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. We have so many transcripts
on the website. Uh so I'm sure that
there's a lot of data out there to be to
be utilized.
>> Yeah.
>> Um All right.
>> I can ask you the next one. It says
>> Yeah. What's the next one here?
>> What's the best approach when starting
on a new target? Generalism or looking
for a specific vulnerability type?
>> Okay. Um
>> and we could fly over some of these like
easier ones. Like we've answered that,
you know, plenty of times in previous
episodes.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I'm just gonna give
it really quickly. Um, it's going to be
generalism, you know, uh, in my opinion
because you need to understand what the
target is is vulnerable to and not every
target's going to have XSS, you know.
Yeah. So,
>> if you're going to do a specific
vulnerability type thing, I think you
need to be open to looking at a lot of
programs and what you do is you just
say, "Hey, my I'm I'm like aggressively
trying to learn SSRF this month. So,
what I'm going to do is I'm going to
spend four hours every morning. I'm
going to switch my targets one time per
day and I'm going to go look for these
things. But, you're going to be less
successful that way. It's not going to
work out that well for you. But, you
might learn more about that that about
that um vulnerability type to then apply
to programs later when you do run across
them. So,
>> yeah. And I think the the telling thing
here is what is their question? Their
question is what's the best approach
when starting a new target? And
actually, let's go let's go look at the
Yeah. What would you say is the best
approach when starting a new target is
what he actually says here rather than
the AI summary.
>> Yeah.
>> Um the answer to that is definitely
generalism, you know,
>> but but if your if your question is
what's the best way to make money,
>> then you know then it gets a little bit
different, right? Well, you know, could
be just check IDOR on every single
program,
>> right?
>> I mean that worked for Zwink clearly.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Right. Um so yeah,
I I I think that it really you got to be
careful with the question you're asking
here. Um,
>> yeah. If you want to own a specific
target, you have to be a journalist
because you don't know what's going to
be vulnerable there.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. And if you want to be a beast,
right, like if you want to be able to
hack anything, you know, then you got to
know a lot of stuff, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Um or but you know, one of one of we're
going to have um uh Zwink on or what was
he now? The Idorminator or
somethingator. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um we're gonna have him on later
this month. Um, and you know, one of the
one of the big pieces of his presence on
Twitter right now has been
>> I'm not a great hacker. You know, he's
like, all I do is just swap, you know, 1
2 3 4 5 into all of this stuff, right?
And that's how I, you know, print money.
Obviously, you know, he's understating
it a little bit. But, um, you know, I
think there's some truth to that where,
you know, you follow patterns that work
and you can get results in bug bounty.
But if your goal is to be the web hacker
that can destroy any target, that is a
diff different goal than I want to print
money and bug bounty.
>> Yep. Yeah. And I think it really applies
to the second question uh which I I
thought was um interestingly asked but
had you know we kind of reframed it. It
was like tips for making half a million
dollars from bug bounty in a year as an
experienced hacker. Yeah.
>> And you know, the question I kind of
reframed it to when we were talking
before the pod was, what would it
require of a bug bounty hunter to make
500k in a year?
>> It's tricky.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think that now that's a
that's a really good question because
most bug hunters want to make more
money, right? But as all things are in
life, it's a trade-off. Like maybe it
would require of you to to hack 12 hours
a day. Maybe it would require of you to
um I don't know learn new things you
haven't learned before, you know, or
push into things you haven't learned
before. Or maybe it would require you to
interface with like you know go and like
ask other people to learn from them and
ask them to collaborate and you know
like there are a lot there are a lot of
um opportunities today because we have
access to people and information more
than ever before but it would require a
ton of work.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
I think I think so. Um,
this would put you in like the top, you
know, point something percent of hunters
if you did this. Definitely in the top
1%.
Um,
I think it's not enough really to
Well, yeah, I think you got to go I
think you have to have strong
capabilities and at least a couple types
of vulnerabilities and you either have
to Well, let me let me give a little bit
nuance to this answer. Okay, I think
>> first you need to go after programs that
are going to pay you good money. So like
ah but see that's not even true because
look at Douglas, right? you know,
Douglas Douglas goes after a bunch of
little programs, you know.
>> Uh I think good money.
>> I think Yeah, I think that that was true
historically, but I still think if you
looked at his average bounties, they
would be significant,
>> you know.
>> Yeah. Okay.
>> Like like you know, like we we talked
about our numbers last um last week or
in the last couple weeks, you know, and
you and I both were around 100 bucks. I
don't think that he's in like the 600
bug range. I think he's in like the two
or 300 bug range, right? So, I still
think that there's still a lot of, you
know, quality that is still there, but
that there's no doubt that if you're
making 500k a year, your average daily
value, this is assuming you work
weekends, is $1,400.
So, you have to make $1,000, $1,400 in
bounties every day on average, right?
And so, if you actually want to do that,
it's going to require a ton of work.
You're going to be need to spitting like
either crazy crits every couple days or
one bug a day that's a medium or a high,
right? And so it's a lot of work.
>> Yeah. Or, and here's the or there, you
got to go after some crazy crazy bugs.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, you got to find some high five
figure, six figure bugs, you know, um to
try to make up for those days when you
can't hunt.
>> Um man, you know, unfortunately, there's
a lot of ways to do it. Here's here's my
recipe, though. I would recommend
hacking on programs that are going to
pay you a decent amount of money. Um,
focusing really hard, going deep on
those programs and focusing on the
assets that are going to have, you know,
obvious impact to the the program. Um,
you need to be pretty effective in your
hunting. You need to not be trying a lot
of things that don't have possibilities
of working. You need to be like churning
out valid attack vectors that have a
decently high chance of working. Um, and
you need to know how to follow these
opportunities when you see them, you
know, that might play out for these
bigger bugs, I think.
>> And you need reports.
>> And you need to write good reports.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So you don't lose yourself
in in the the whole like arguing with
triage thing. I agree.
>> Um, good question, Quickseker. Thank
you. Um, all right. Does AI and vibe
coding introduce a new era of bug bounty
hunting with more bugs to find uh Dusk
from Dusk Raider? Give me a quick answer
on this.
>> Yeah, we we we kind of we kind of talked
about that. I definitely think um that
we're in the AI slop era of bugs. I
think that in a year or two, AI systems
are going to be writing way fewer bugs,
right? And right now, we've got tons of
people writing tons of apps using
adorite code. Nearly everyone I know who
works at big companies is also using AI
code and it's not great at thinking
about things like business logic IDOR
those sort of things. So I definitely
think that it um introduces a new era
and on top of that me and lots of
friends are finding vulnerabilities in
um new AI apps right there are there
actually like new types of
vulnerabilities and then I think we have
crazy people like um Arc was that their
name?
um yeah, yeah, finding insane vectors
like that. And so, uh it does feel like
a little bit of a new era in my opinion.
And so, I think there, you know, there
will be lots of lots of vulnerabilities
in that way.
>> Yeah, totally agree with you there. Um
let's move to this next one from
Tenacious Outlaw. Yeah.
>> Um our AI summary of that says, "Why are
you in the human in the loop plus AI
camp while Reszo is in more of the AI
will solve web security camp?" Um is
this an actual accurate representation
of your perspective.
>> I mean, pro probably not, but I'm I'm
super happy to defend it. I do think
that there is a tipping point at which
it's cheaper to run, you know, a hackbot
than the amount of vulnerability uh or
sorry, bug bounty payouts that come out
of that system and then you can scale it
infinitely. And, you know, I always call
that like the oh, I don't even remember
what I call it now,
>> but apocalypse for bug bounty.
>> No, no, no, no. But, you know, and
that's going to happen a few different
times, right? because then you run it
and then once those bugs are found then
it doesn't the tipping point's not there
anymore so you have to improve your
hackbot and then you can run it again
and so I do think that that can happen
kind of like um at some point but I do
think that human in the loop is going to
be huge right like the reason why you're
able to quickly find that bug that you
talked about during your presentation
for HomCon was because you pointed it at
something that you saw was potentially
vulnerable right like your human
intuition pointed it directly at the
thing that was vulnerable when you could
have I mean how How many things could
you have pointed at? How many headers
were in that request? How many requests
did that app make? Right? You pointed it
at that request with that header and
asked it to. So there's no doubt that
it's both and but uh yeah.
>> Yeah. It's interesting because if it
scales infinitely, right, like if if
compute just becomes like super duper
duper derp cheap, you can just run it on
everything. you can just say every
single cookie like try to hack it, you
know, with this, you know, and and uh
and I think that will be a weird spot,
you know, to be in.
>> Um
>> but overall, I think for the next 5 10
years, human in the loop plus AI is
going to be massive at least. Um yeah.
Um all right, let's look at some of
these ones here. Um, when you open a new
program without tools, what exact
questions are you asking yourself to
mentally map the attack surface? This is
from Silent Dragon. Let me see if I can
find that one over here.
Um,
I'm trying to emulate the user.
>> Yeah. It says, "When you open a new
program and intentionally delay using
any tools is like the actual question."
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I I think I think that I'm really
trying to emulate the user, you know,
like I'm really trying to put myself in
their shoes, you know. It's funny. I I I
I did acting in musical theater in uh in
high school, and I think a little bit of
this helps, you know, like I think I'm
like, "All right, now I am the user of
this app, you know, embody that
character. Let's go." you know, like and
and you try to come up with, you know,
what kind of stuff the end user would be
doing and what goals they might have and
you try to use that to learn about the
app.
>> Um, what about you? What do you think?
>> Yeah, I I mean, I think something
similar. I do think I'm like, you know,
less strong at that. Like I have less
discipline. A lot of times I'll get in
there and just like get w pig and hold
on like interesting requests and stuff
rather than like going through the time
to like fully use the app end to end in
a way that a user would. Um, and I think
that does hinder me deeper into live
events where, you know, you want to get
to the functionality that only 10% of
the people are looking at, right? Um, by
by doing that exact thing, right?
Setting up this, you know, video game
front store including all of the assets
and all of the uploads and the patches
and all the things, right? To like
really see that actual functionality.
Um, but yeah, I mean, yeah, it's a
simple question. I think your answer was
was fantastic.
Their follow-up question is the
interesting one though.
>> We talked about that. Are there any
specific mental antiatterns you learn to
avoid that look smart but consistently
waste time?
>> Yeah, that is a good question. That that
might take question of AMA silent.
I I think that's a really good question.
Um the one that we talk about all the
time is eternal learning and eternal
recon, right? like
you know it seems to make sense for you
to like all right I need to learn a lot
of stuff about bug bounty right and uh I
need to learn or I need to try to find
the most vulnerable asset so I'm going
to spend a good amount of time on recon
really it's not it's not what you're
what you should do you know it's a
pitfall really what you should do is is
get in there focus on the main app focus
on in my opinion this is my opinion a
lot of people have different of opinions
but um especially spending too much time
on recon on is is going to be really bad
for hunters and and it really poisons
them too. Um I've got I've got a couple
people I've worked with that are just
really stuck in the recon world and it's
hard to pull them out. Um I think
because I've been there I've been there
and I actually made it work, you know,
for a long time. I I do more of both
now. But I think the reason why it's so
addicting is because it's like gambling.
It's like panning for gold. And when you
find that gold, you know, and and all
hacking, all hacking kind of is, but
there's like it just feels like manual
hacking is more of like the hard work.
Like you've got to pick and you're like
hitting the rock looking for gold. It
feels like recon. It feels like you're
just like like it's more like panning,
you know? You just shove it down in the
water and see if something's there.
Shove it in the water and see if
something's there. It's like not as
hard.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> It's like it's like it's like mining
versus panning. Yeah.
>> But all of Bug Bounty is kind of like
gambling, you know? like, you know, it
really is. So, yeah, I think it's I
think it's just a pitfall personally.
And then the other one that I had was
writing actually everything down,
>> you know, like I've seen I mean,
obviously there are people like Brandon,
you know, Gret me who um make a lot of
progress in their hunting based off of
taking good notes and you know, that's
how that integrates with their mind.
I've seen a couple hackers that just
literally write everything.
>> Mhm.
>> I think that is not good. I think
there's some way you need to try to
trust your intuition and your vibe
>> on the target um to really be effective
about it and and especially if you're
taking a lot of time to like
>> actually write it out like
>> I don't know if that's a good use of
your time.
>> I had another antiattern that came to me
whenever we were reading the question
just now that I think that you're going
to love to talk about because you're so
good at doing the opposite.
>> I How would you define the antiattern of
pigeon holeing? Like I think that you're
like ruthless in your prioritization of
your time and I don't see that in other
hackers and I think it hinders them. It
hinders me sometimes and so how would
you like define that class of or that
that class of antiattern?
>> I think sometimes people can feel
intellectual like trying a thousand
payloads on a parameter sometimes
when they just need to move on you know.
>> Yeah.
>> But I don't know what
>> Yeah. I don't know man. I mean, a lot of
that's hacker intuition and experience,
right?
>> Um, I don't know what to say beyond
besides that. I feel like most people
suffer from the inverse problem more
than the pigeon holding problem.
>> Okay. Well, here's the thing. We were
sitting in Tokyo.
>> Yeah.
>> We ended we ended up winning MBH.
>> But you you looked at me and Kieran, you
were like, "Stop working on that. Work
on this."
>> So, what's what's the anti pattern you
were breaking there?
>> Was it what was it like?
>> It's impact alignment, too, man. I mean
it really
>> I think it's impact. Yeah. Don't focus
on what's interesting or what's new.
Focus on what is going to have the
higher impact.
>> Yeah. Or something that's going to be
vulnerable, you know, like like you know
you like you guys were looking at
something that was likely going to be
vulnerable, right? But the impact in in
alignment with the goals of the LH was
not as on point.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and
>> like like it was going to come out as a
medium and it wasn't something that that
it had the bonus on it or that they
cared about or whatever.
>> Exactly. and and we had leads in valid
areas, you know. Um, so that's why I
kind of redirected you guys there.
>> Um,
>> and yeah, I I think ruthless alignment
to impact, you know, what what the
target what you need to accomplish with
the target, I think is is a very high
signal like trait.
>> Um, you know, maybe um and it can be in
alignment with pigeon pigeon holeing,
right? just kind of going down, you
know, super deep on something and
hyperfocusing on it. But
>> yeah, I think the the best way I found
to do that in my life is ask myself like
the question of if I do achieve what I'm
trying to achieve here, what would the
impact be
>> because you can be trying things that
even if it works aren't going to be a
bug or trying things if it does work
would be a medium,
>> right? Because like you're looking at
something that's post off and requires
user interaction and you're just like
spending hours on this thing. It's like,
dude, even if you popped it, it's going
to be immediate at most. Just move on.
>> Yeah. And and if and you know, you got
to be honest with yourself about it,
too, because it's very easy to get
googly eyes at these, you know, attack
vectors sometimes and be like, "No, no,
this is a great bug. This is a great
bug. All they've got to do is click 47
things, you know, like,
>> you know." Uh, so definitely being
honest with yourself about that is a big
piece. Um,
>> yeah.
I I I I think I had one more one more
thing on that. Um, oh yeah, the the
thing I was going to say about this is
if you do find yourself maybe like
rabbit holeing or whatever, um,
you may take a step forward in the chain
and and simulate, you know, this one
piece being done if you can and and see
if you actually do have a valid bug,
like, you know, uh, you know, apply a
match and replace rule or something,
assuming you're able to bypass some, you
know, logic or whatever, right? Um, and
see if you actually do have like a valid
bug with the whole chain before you go
all the way down on this one piece that
you need to to break, you know?
>> Yeah, because a lot of times you'll have
that aha moment and you say, "Oh, it
wouldn't have worked anyways now. You
just saved yourself so long."
>> Exactly. I think that's important.
>> Yep.
>> Great question, Silent Dragon.
>> Um, man, his next question here too is
really good. What was one specific
belief you had about Bug Bounty that
turned out to be wrong and once you
dropped it, your results noticeably
changed?
Freicky,
>> I really liked the expo presentation
where they outlined these for agents,
you know, and I think it was their
Defvcon talk that they didn't actually
get to give, but they posted it on
YouTube afterwards. Um, they highlighted
specific breakthroughs that they had
with the product. I really like that.
Um,
I'm trying to identify one in
particular. I think that one thing
that's interesting is that I would have
believed that
there was more um variation in mindset.
But when you are at these live events
and you're sitting with other top
hackers and they are
>> they're thinking in the exact same terms
as you. Like I've had so many moments
sitting there in front of somebody's
laptop and I'm starting to say, "Now try
this." And they're typing that exact
thing. Or you see two other people do
that. One person's like, "Oh, you should
try this." And the other person's
already trying it. Um,
>> yeah.
>> And that to me makes it feel more
achievable. It's like, oh, I'm not so
distantly removed from this person and
they're just like epically way better
than me and I can't do it. I think that
kind of um, so I think imposter syndrome
is a good is a good answer to this
question that they're asking. Um,
>> yeah, it's like one thing that I believe
was that I was was not able to or you
know, whatever, but in fact, you
actually can if you if you try.
>> Yeah.
I don't know if I have a specific belief
that I felt like was near and dear to my
heart that once I dropped, you know,
realized it was wrong. Um,
that I I saw the results changed
noticeably. From like a technical
perspective, I will say from a
non-technical perspective, I believed
that I needed to be successful in Boke
Bounty to respect myself as a as a
hacker. you know, I needed to be winning
every live hacking event and stuff like
that. And I think that's too much
pressure.
>> And um I think once I put my self-worth
in something else, right, we you and I,
you know, for you and I it's our
relationship with Jesus, but for a lot
of other people, it's it's their, you
know, um it's their religion or it's
their, you know, relationships or their,
you know, something more stable than bug
bounty. Like bug bounty is just such a
crappy thing to put your self worth in
because it's so volatile. Mhm.
>> You know, um,
>> and there are incredible hackers that
you don't see that don't find bugs at
events, right? Like it's not it's not a
game where just because you are skilled
means you definitely will succeed. There
is like a little bit of an element of,
you know, um,
>> yeah,
>> of like where you chose to spend your
time.
>> Absolutely. Yeah. So, check your self
worth. I think that that's probably my
best answer to that.
Um, all right. Let's let's take these
last couple ones rapid fire and wrap up
this episode so we don't give uh Richard
too long of an episode edit this week
because it's we're pushing it out last
minute. Um, how do you tackle small
scope functionality?
>> That one's for you. I think you've taken
some small scope before with me with
small scope. I move on. If I if it's
small scope and I don't feel like I'm an
expert at it or I'm struggling. I the
the and actually this is kind of a tip
for people too who are starting Bug
Bounty. If something's not your cup of
tea, like you don't have to stay on it.
Like there's lots of other stuff.
>> You know, Justin has this like goal and
desire to do well at events even when
the scope is crap. And you know, not
everyone has to live by that same
philosophy. I personally don't. But and
I that's an admirable trait in Justin.
But so I would just say you don't have
to. But if you're going to, how should
they tackle it, Justin?
>> Yeah, I would say um I mean you've just
got a grasp at straws is pretty much the
only thing I can tell you. like find
every little little oddity or little
like quirk that you can find and see
what you can make out of it. Um,
and I think that's a little fun, you
know, to prove to yourself,
>> right? I I think sometimes, especially
if you're a little bit like you're an
intermediate, upper intermediate hacker
and you've got something you really want
to pone, like just banging your head
into it until you pone it is feels
pretty good.
>> Yeah. Um, and as far as hitting
criticals, sometimes the criticals
aren't going to be there. If the
functionality is not there, the crit the
criticals may not be there. Um, but
definitely try things you don't normally
try. Think outside the box. Really put
yourselves in the shoes of the
developer. Um, and that's how you kind
of work around these these small scope
targets.
>> Yeah.
>> Um,
>> all right. Let me ask you this one. How
long do you stay on one program before
moving to the new one? Joseph,
>> if it's like an actual new program, like
a new invite or something, um,
I would say as short as a couple hours,
as long as, you know, a couple days. I
don't think that people should be
whipping themselves into locking into a
new program for a long time. I think
that's a really bad idea because
oftentimes the companies will end up
skirting around the bugs or having like
a really weird duping policy where all
your stuff gets duped. If it's like an
anchor program for other hackers that
you know, then I think going along on
that's totally fine. But if it is a new
program, I do not recommend that. In
fact, I would say it's better to
>> um spend a few hours on it, submit a
couple bugs if you have some, and then
go back to an anchor program or another
new one and then if they treat you well,
come back to it, right? or maybe it's
worth your ROI if it's like pretty
vulnerable to go ahead and farm it for
two days or whatever, but I would not at
that point stress yourself out. I would
then move on to something else until
they've like kind of proven that they're
going to treat you well.
>> Yeah, I agree. I think that's a good
one. Um,
>> you do this one. Do you recommend using
additional proxies besides Burp and
Kaido?
>> Uh, no. I would recommend you use Burp
or Kaido. Um, I I would say that there's
a new one on the scene. I don't know
that I like consider this like an actual
proxy or whatever, but Rep plus I
believe is the name of it. It's a you
know Chrome extension that kind of tries
to emulate what these proxies are doing.
Yeah.
>> Uh but you can't write arbitrary HTTP
requests because of limitations on like
the fetch stack that they're using to
send the request. So it's a little
tricky, but like if you were in a
pickle, you could try using that. I
think that um you know if you're doing
system type proxying like sometimes you
need to proxy the whole system because
you're I don't know I've seen people use
like other weird proxies for things like
that like there are some proxies that
make it slightly easier to proxy your
whole system or if you're on mobile or
something but no if you're doing web
hacking um definitely use one of the
main stays you know we're big fans of
Kaido these days
>> I'm wearing the future today
>> nice dude very good yeah I think this
one could be interesting you know rep
plus could be interesting for like quick
and dirty stuff when you don't have
access to a full um a full, you know,
Kaido setup, but uh it's not going to
have a lot of the more robust features
that you might need. Um all right, next
one is how many programs do you
recommend focusing on at once, Joseph?
How many programs do you recommend
focusing on at once?
>> It depends what you mean by at once,
right? I mean, only one at once.
Actually, it's kind of frustrating
whenever you get message leads for other
programs and you've already got like
Kaido or Bart pulled up and you don't
want to like at least in Kaido you can
switch um projects pretty easily, but
it's still pretty annoying to me. I
start like mixing my traffic and getting
all this on. If you if it means like uh
you know over the course of like a few,
you know, days or weeks, this is like
something we talked about in our end of
year episode. My goal is to actually
come up with some anchor programs this
year rather than than bouncing around.
What do you think?
>> Yeah. Um I think I mean pretty much
exclusively you got to focus on one
program. Yeah.
>> Uh you know
>> there are exceptions when opportunity
>> if you're spraying a vulnerability like
there's no CV it's like a one day and
you know it's going to get paid out and
you're going to spray it across all
programs that's different right. But
>> yeah. Yeah. I agree. I agree. Um how do
you pick up bug bounties after a long
break? Um
>> this is super relevant to me.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm back at work today.
>> Yeah. Tricky. Um, you get curious, you
get hype, you trigger your love of Bug
Bounty, and you claw at your computer
desk, you know? Like, I don't know, man.
I just love this [__] Like, I like if
I've had a long break, I just try to
focus on how passionate I am about all
of this.
>> Um, yeah, I think that's my go-to.
>> I'm usually super anti to get back to
it. Um, I think I think Gret me or
somebody else, maybe Kieran Monkey,
somebody said that they will do a a pin
test to get back into it. I I don't know
if that necessarily worked for me, but
yeah, usually I'm like so antsy to get
back to it that I want to that um I'm
curious. Though, I did hear a really
cool thing. It was on the Chris
Williamson podcast. He was he was
interviewing Huberman and he said if
you're about to go into a period of
learning, it's you want some boredom
beforehand and afterwards. Um you want
the boredom, you want the boredom
beforehand
>> because if you've been like scrolling
TikTok reels, you're not going to find
this like technical content interesting.
Wow, that's a great point, right? And so
if you have some opportunity to go for a
walk without your phone or whatever
before you come to your desk to do some
learning, I think that's great.
>> And said you want some dead space
afterwards to really process it. I think
those are both smart things. I think
that it also could apply to bug bounty.
Like if you've been starving yourself of
dopamine for like 30 minutes or an hour
or something, then when you get to your
computer and you start seeing like, you
know, the potential for money in the in
these like HTTP requests, I think you're
going to be more excited than if you
just been watching a YouTube video of
like, you know, your favorite video game
or whatever. So, I think that that's
like kind of like a fun little just like
life hack there.
>> Yeah, that that is good. I like that.
Put a little bit of of boredom adjacent
to it. That's good.
>> Yeah.
>> Um All right. I think the last one that
we'll do is when should you give up on a
bug that's been ignored by triagers?
Look, I've like I'm gonna be honest with
you guys. I've never had a bug that is
actually valid be ignored by triagers
for a long time. So, if if the triagers
are eternally, you know, forever
ignoring your bug, it's probably not a
valid bug.
>> Yeah. you you have either done an
extremely poor job of articulating it
>> or you've overinflated the the the the
severity in your mind and so it's
actually a low and so they're just not
getting to it because all the other
reports are much more important.
>> Justin, I hate to do this. You did we
did I only highlighted two questions
that I really wanted to answer and we
didn't answer one of them.
>> Oh no, dude. I'm sorry. I jumped over
it. My bad.
>> You're good.
>> Okay, let me let me ask you this then.
Yes.
>> What invisible elements in a report
usually make the difference between a 2K
payout and a 20k payout? I so I have a
lot to say here. One, I think that
you're uniquely good at it. I do think
that it's something that would worked
well for me and my advantage of like
coming up in Bug Bounty. But I think
that the number one thing that jumps my
mind is just try to reproduce it via
your steps once. It's not that hard
because you probably forgot something.
the number of times that, you know, I've
had to respond to an NMI or and like
even if the triager only has to request
more information, your report one time,
I think it honestly changes the way they
view your report in their head for some
reason.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like if they can very easily
reproduce it instantly. I think that it
will sometimes actually shade their
opinion of the severity, even if it ends
up being the exact same bug, but they
just had to send it back to you once
because you like left out a step.
>> Wow, dude. Yeah, totally. That that's
Yeah, 100%.
>> Like if you just forgot to tell them to
like go into the profile and then go
click the edit button to get to that
request that they needed,
>> they almost I think will just
subconsciously view that report as like
less than because like they had to send
it back to you for some reason. And so I
would just say always reproduce your bug
via the steps alone. Like play ignorant,
put yourself in the shoes of the triager
and Justin's acting advice and then go
in and just do the bug one time to one.
make sure it still works because
sometimes I know you've had this happen.
You go back to reproduce and it doesn't
reproduce and you swap the cookies
incorrectly or whatever. So that's
useful to do in general to make sure you
don't get a notlicable but when you're
doing that you'll be like, "Oh, I didn't
tell them to click here before they
clicked here in order to get that thing
right."
>> Yeah, I think that's a great point. I
think I think doubling down also into
your PC, you know, giving them a script
where they run it and then it just
outputs PII, you know, of other people
like that that just feels really bad,
you know.
>> It does. Yeah. Yeah. So add PC and video
if it's critical enough that it's worth
your time to do so.
>> Yeah. Try to make it look as simple as
possible to exploit, you know, because
that that's the obvious, you know, best
scenario is stupid simple to exploit,
very high impact, right? And some of the
time, you know, it's it's complicated to
exploit and high impact, right? And in
those scenarios, you really want to
automate the PC to make it look as
simple as possible.
>> Um, so that could be a big a big
difference. Um, the other thing that I
can say is
>> spending a good amount of time on your
impact assessment.
>> Yeah.
>> Describing what kind of data you can
get, what you can do with it. Don't just
like pop up an O token, you know, show
say, hey, this is the O token. You know,
here's how you set it in your browser
and now you're a user. or you know
here's this token I can swap it for this
and now I'm in this you know in this
account right
>> um
>> yeah I remember the first time
>> that I had that experience um was I had
found a vulnerability that I was like I
don't know maybe this is a medium or
something and I sent it to mayonnaise or
my own eyes depending how you want to
pronounce it and he was like dude this
is obviously critical here's how you
have to articulate it to their team and
he like wrote out like two paragraphs
for me that was like
>> you know the impact that this has on the
advertisers when they're going to
advertise this. If they if this was
disabled, it would actually, you know,
reduce their earnings in the month by
millions of dollars because these are
the customers, you know, like just
getting into the nitty-gritty details
for the actual impact there, I think is
something that you do well and something
that um will result in much higher
payouts.
>> Yeah, totally, man. Okay, cool. That's a
wrap. I'm sorry for skipping that one. I
did want to add at the end here, Viral
Element asks, "Any good worship songs
you can recommend?" So, for our
Christian listeners, um, one of the ones
that my church has been running, uh, is
Alive Forever in Amen by, uh, Travis
Cotrell, which is super good. That's a
vibe. Um, I don't know, man. It's hard
when you're when you're put on the spot.
I saw it here and I spent a second like
thinking about it. Does anything come to
mind off the top of your head?
>> I honestly have never been a person who
remembers song names.
>> Yeah.
>> Or or or even artist names. But I will
say that with me and the kids in the
car, I have just been totally obsessed
with Forest Frank for like weeks. Oh
yeah.
>> Like I the the the the uh the messages
are so deeply biblical, but then it
feels like a fun song that you can dance
to or have fun to. Um
>> and uh this is uh um Anyways, I also
just love like big bass. All of my
friends had cars with like big
subsystems and so in the in the Tesla
Model Y has a really good bass and so I
crank up the bass and it just feels like
I'm like, you know, jamming around,
zooming to to worship music. So, it's
sick. But
>> that's awesome, man. That feels great.
All right, man. I think that's a wrap on
this episode. Um, thanks to everybody
who submitted questions. I don't know
who you your actual handles are, but we
tried to call you out as much as we
could. Um, appreciate you guys
participating.
>> Yeah, absolutely. Go check out
bugbounty.
>> Yeah, for sure. All right. Peace.
>> Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.